Guide to the American Federation of Teachers, Local 3882 (Clerical Union) Records WAG.071
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
American Federation of Teachers, Local 3882 (Clerical Union) Records
1979-2007
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
American Federation of Teachers. Local 3882 (Clerical Union)
Loane, Scott
WAG.071
14 Linear Feet in 14 record cartons
4 websites in four archived websites.
The American Federation of Teachers (AFT) Local 3882 is a New York City local of the national labor union representing teachers. Locally known as the United Staff Association (USA) of New York University, the branch won representation of office, clerical, technical, and laboratory employees at NYU in December 1978. This collection documents the local's activities and consists of subject files; leaflets, publications, and other promotional literature; labor reports produced by NYU; administrative files, including correspondence, meeting minutes, and member literature; files on grievances, arbitrations, and related labor practices; organizer's files, including calendars and diaries; and files on strikes and contract negotiations, including materials on a strike in 1988.
Scope and Content Note
This collection documents the activities of the American Federation of Teachers, Local 3882 (also known as the United Staff Association of NYU) during the late 1970s through the late 1990s. The collection consists of subject files; leaflets, publications, and other promotional literature; labor reports produced by NYU; administrative files, including correspondence, meeting minutes, and member literature; files on grievances, arbitrations, and related labor practices; organizer's files, including calendars and diaries; and files on strikes and contract negotiations, including materials on a strike in 1988. The collection also includes the union's websites and blog, captured from 2007 to the present day.
Audiovisual Access Policies and Procedures
Audiovisual materials have not been preserved and may not be available to researchers. Materials not yet digitized will need to have access copies made before they can be used. To request an access copy, or if you are unsure if an item has been digitized, please contact tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu, (212) 998-2630 with the collection name, collection number, and a description of the item(s) requested. A staff member will respond to you with further information.
Arrangement
This collection has not been arranged by an archivist. The materials are arranged in the order in which they were received from the donor.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Historical/Biographical Note
The American Federation of Teachers (AFT) Local 3882 is a New York City local of the national labor union representing teachers. Locally known as the United Staff Association (USA) of New York University, the branch won representation of office, clerical, technical, and laboratory employees at NYU in December 1978. The USA negotiated its first contract in 1979, with year-to-year contracts in place until 1983. The union hired its first full-time employee, an organizer in August 1984. Presidents of the local have included Christine Russell (1978-1980), John Kraft (1980-1985), and Margarita Aguilar (1985).
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by Scott Loane on behalf of the American Federation of Teachers, Local 3882, in 1997. The accession numbers associated with this gift are 1997.056 and 1997.057.
In addition, the accession number 1997.054 is also associated with this collection.
Websites were initially selected by curators and captured through the use of The California Digital Library's Web Archiving Service in 2007 as part of the Labor Unions and Organizations (U.S.) Web Archive. In 2015, these websites were migrated to Archive-It. In circa, 2015, the original URLS for the website, http://www.aft3882.org/index.shtml, http://www.aft3882.org/, and http://ucats3882.blogspot.com/ became defunct. Archive-It uses web crawling technology to capture websites at a scheduled time and displays only an archived copy, from the resulting WARC file, of the website. In 2018, the new URL, http://ucats3882.org/, was added to the web archive. The accession number associated with the website is 2019.096.
Take Down Policy
If you hold the rights to materials in our archived websites that are unattributed, please let us know so that we may maintain accurate information about these materials.
If you are a rights holder and are concerned that you have found material on this website for which you have not granted permission (or is not covered by a copyright exception under US copyright laws), you may request the removal of the material from our site by submitting a notice, with the elements described below, to the repository email.
Please include the following in your notice: Identification of the material that you believe to be infringing and information sufficient to permit us to locate the material; your contact information, such as an address, telephone number, and email address; a statement that you are the owner, or authorized to act on behalf of the owner, of an exclusive right that is allegedly infringed and that you have a good-faith belief that use of the material in the manner complained of is not authorized by the copyright owner, its agent, or the law; a statement that the information in the notification is accurate and made under penalty of perjury; and your physical or electronic signature. Upon receiving a notice that includes the details listed above, we will remove the allegedly infringing material from public view while we assess the issues identified in your notice.
Labor unions -- New York (State) -- New York -- History -- 20th century.; Universities and colleges |x Employees |x Labor unions |z New York (State) |z New York.; New York University; American Federation of Teachers; American Federation of Teachers. Local 3882 (Clerical Union); Loane, Scott
- United Staff Association of NYU, Subject Files, Negotiations, 1979-1987 (Box 1, Box 2)
- Undescribed Materials, undated (Box 12, Box 5, Box 3, Box 13)
- Leaflets, 1979-1987 (Box 4)
- United Staff Association of NYU, General Union, Reference Files, Solidarity Campaign, undated (Box 6)
- Officer Calendars, Organizer's Diary, Photographs, 1980-1988 (Box 7)
- 1988 Negotiations and Strike (Box 8, Box 14)
- 1990 and 1993 Negotiations, 1990-1993 (Box 9)
- 1990 Negotiations, Information Requests (Box 10)
- 1993 Contract Negotiations (Box 11)
- 1996 Contract Negotiations (Box 16)
- Archived Websites, September 2007-ongoing; 4 websites in four archived websites (Box Electronic Records)
  Scope and Content Note
  Union of Clerical, Administrative & Technical Staff, Local 3882,, NYSUT, AFT, AFL-CIO (UCATS), founded in 1978, is a labor union that represents over 1500 clerical, administrative, and technical staff at New York University. They are affiliated with the American Federation of Teachers and were formerly known as the United Staff Association of NYU. The website contains the current contract, their newsletter, Momentum, and their blog.
  Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
  Due to technical or privacy issues, archived websites may not be exact copies of the original website at the time of the web crawl. Certain file types will not be captured dependent on how they are embedded in the site. Other parts of websites that the crawler has difficulty capturing includes Javascript, streaming content, database-driven content, and highly interactive content. Full-Text searches of archived websites are available at https://archive-it.org/organizations/567.
  Accruals
  New site crawls are accrued semiannually.
  Appraisal
  Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of http://ucats3882.org/ in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.